Dhruv Bahl Speak\_

bhldhruv@gmail.com | 2508990360 | LinkedIn | Github | Kelowna, BC | He/Him

## **Summary**

A 4th year computer science major at the University of British Columbia with 1.5 years work experience through internships involving database querying, APIs and testing and a personal interest in becoming a full stack developer

**Skills** (Years of experience listed after each item.)

Languages: Python 0.5 | JavaScript 0.5 | Java 2 | C# 1

Frameworks: React 1 |

Databases: MongoDB 0.5 | MySql 1

Other: Git 2 | Agile 1

#### **Education**

BSc in Computing, Computer Science, Graduation: 05/2023

University Of British Columbia, Canada

• GPA: 3.3 / 4.00

Outstanding International Student award

#### **Experience**

Microsoft - Kelowna, British Columbia | Engineering Intern | 05/2020 - 08/2020

- Developed a program that can detect anomalies from transactional data using C# and SQL and displayed the anomalies on a webpage provided by Microsoft.
- Set up rule-based filtering that included filters based on unusually large purchase orders as well as random spikes in the tax rate to prevent displeased customers and loss of contracts.
- This is a company requirement and has saved on-call engineers time by 50% as the anomaly information
  was available on the webpage.

Microsoft - Kelowna, British Columbia | Engineering Intern | 05/2021 - 08/2021

- Responsible for the creation of an API using C#. The API's role was to change the payment date for an order
  if a new future date has been provided.
- Helped reduce clients' products from being disabled incorrectly.
- Created an end-to-end anomaly detection service that used technologies such as SCOPE and Azure Data Factory as well as C# to create another API with a similar implementation.

Skytrac - Kelowna, BC | Hardware/Software Test Co-op | 01/2022 - 12/2022

- Created a python script to identify high periods of latency in a csv file which reduces testing time for testers by 20% each time the test is run.
- Added to Skytrac's suite of Selenium test cases to test their flight tracking website. These automated test
  cases test the functionality of Skyweb (A flight tracking service). This will help reduce the time spent on
  these tests by testers by up to 200 hours.

Resume powered by Speak\_

Dhruv Bahl Speak\_

• Contributed to the development of a software test tool (Avionic Data Bus Simulator) using C#. On completion, the test tool is estimated to be able to create 2000 tests a day

# **Projects**

## CheckLick | Capstone

- Implemented and redesigned 6 webpages by adding the CSS framework, Bootstrap, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement compared to before.
- Participated in each step of the product development process from the group ideation to developing improvements for features that reach thousands of customers.

## Free Resume Builder | Personal Project

- Solo project to understand and improve my knowledge of the MERN stack.
- Created Dynamic Web Pages to allow free and easy resume creation
- Continuously working on this to add increased functionality.

## The Snake Game | Personal Project

- Solo project to understand and improve my knowledge of Java's OOP structure and its GUI.
- A continuous project as I aim to add more features to make it more fun and continuously tap into the creative part of my mind.